# RYAN H S

mr.ryansilalahi@gmail.com (62) - 85720759240

#### RESEARCHER / SR. WEB DEVELOPER

Profile

Senior PHP Developer who likes to push the limit of "development" since 2011.

Skills

Web Developer

Work in web development since 2011.

C Programmer

Some project need critical mission where C is the best solution. No doubt about it.

Research / (AI)

Back to study for master degree to pursuit my goal as researcher. Especially in AI.

**Technical** 

HTML5	Laravel	Linux
Javascript / React JS	CodeIgniter	Windows
SASS & LESS	C for Web	

#### Experience

#### Pasebandotcom

PHP Programmer

Apr, 2011 - Dec, 2011

"Was" social media website in Indonesia. The company gave me opportunity for my first full-time job and taught me development for real projects.

#### CV Pusat Link & CV Techno

Full Stack Programmer (System & Web)

Jan, 2012 - Aug, 2012

"Was" a startup company to build data package (mobile) and other products payments, connect to banks & service providers, and retail stores.

## PT Topi Putih Kreasi Indonesia

Web Programmer, Technical advisor

Oct, 2012 - Jan, 2014

This was a small company in Indonesia with rapid development for many projects. This company honed me to have a habit to work hard and dedicate myself to every project i work on.

## PT Voxteneo Indonesia

PHP Programmer

Sep, 2014 - Jul, 2015

My first experience to work fully for European clients, Belgium company in Indonesia "branch". I learnt many things in this company, from professional development to work in a big team across the world. Quit only because i want to do master degree, really good experience there.

## Universitas Internasional Batam

Lecturer & Web Developer

Aug, 2016 - May, 2017

Due to seamolec scholarship, I had to do internship at a region in Indonesia for 2 semester. I worked there as lecturer for undergraduate student for 2 classes every semester and develop web apps for university's internal applications.

## SCCIC Lab - Institut Teknologi Bandung

February, 2018 - May, 2018

Researcher & Web Developer

Upon master degree graduation i work as researcher in this Lab to hone my skills related to Artificial Intelligence and develop habit of how researcher works.

#### **Education**

#### SMKN 4 Bandung - (Vocational High School)

Rekayasa Perangkat Lunak (Software Engineering)

## STMIK "amikbandung" - (Bachelor Degree)

Teknik Informatika (Computer Science/Informatics) 3.53/4.00 GPA

## Institut Teknologi Bandung - (Master Degree)

Teknik Elektro Option Teknologi Media Dijital dan Game 3.42/4.00 GPA

#### Awardee

## Mahasiswa Program Beasiswa Unggulan, yang Mendapat Prestasi di Bidang

Teknologi Informasi BPKLN Kemdikbud RI **2012** 

#### **Scholarships**

#### Beasiswa Unggulan, Bachelor Degree

Beasiswa Unggulan Masyarakat Berprestasi is a scholarship from goverment for Bachelor, Master and Doctoral. https://beasiswaunggulan.kemdikbud.go.id/

#### Seamolec, Master Degree

SEAMEO Regional Open Learning Centre (SEAMOLEC) is one of the 24 Centres under the auspices of Southeast Asian Ministers of Education Organization (SEAMEO) focusing in the field of Open and Distance Learning (ODL). https://www.seamolec.org/

#### Volunteer

## Lead Developer/Web Programmer - PPDB Kota Bandung

Local Education Authority trusted me to work on students registration projects (from elementary to junior to senior).

Since second year i became lead developer for this project. As a team we tweaked the website as hard as we can to make sure the website run smoothly for this events that held  $1 \mod 1$ 

## Lead Developer/Web Programmer - PPDB SMK Jawa Barat

In 2017 Local Education Authority in region trusted my team to work not only Bandung but for whole region (West Java). (The system created in pure C since 2014)

Noted Open Source Contribution chess.php

chess.php is a PHP chess library that is used for chess move generation/validation, piece placement/movement, and check/checkmate/stalemate detection - basically everything but the AI. (Ported from chess.js)

#### cweb

Web Server (API Apps/application) in pure C. (legacy)

### Encyclopedia (jsclasses inovation award)

This object can store large objects in many smaller ones. It acts like an object that stores key-value pairs but internally it creates multiple objects of limited length when the the number of entries exceeds the configured object limit. The object provides functions to set and get key values, check if a key exists, remove a value with a given key, and traverse the object entries using a callback function.

# Seminar Portfolio (as speaker)

Hacking Black or White UNPAD 2009

Make Your Linux Powerfull UNPAD 2010

Web Design and Security in 2014 and Web Hacking Demo STMIK "amikbandung" 2013

The Future of Android Universitas Sangga Buana **2014** 

# Workshop Portfolio (as trainer)

Workshop Hacking STMIK "amikbandung" **08-19 February 2010** 

Workshop Hacking STMIK "amikbandung" **01-12 March 2010** 

## **Publication**

Domain Event Driven pada Aplikasi Komputer Catur: Logika Catur Tati Suprapti, Ryan H. Silalahi. KOPERTIP INDONESIA. Jan 01, 2017

Optimization and modification of evaluation function in Stockfish chess engine U Asmi, AS Prihatmanto, R H Silalahi. IEEE. Dec 01, 2016

Komparasi Algoritma Pengurutan untuk Penerimaan Peserta Didik Baru Kota Bandung

Ryan H. Silalahi, Tati Suprapti. Universitas Jenderal Achmad Yani. Apr 01, 2015